## PRUDHVI RAJ MARGANI

prudhvirajmargani973@gmail.com | in /prudhvi-raj-margani | 7 /prudhviraj-margani

## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Passionate software professional with nearly 4 years of experience, seeking a challenging position in a reputable organization where I can further develop my expertise, expand my learning, knowledge, skills, and training to contribute to the organization's growth.

## **EDUCATION**

## Lakireddy Bali Reedy College of Engineering

2017 - 2021

Bachelors in Computer Science & Engineering

8.7/10

### **SKILLS**

#### **Technical Skills:**

Java, Spring Boot, RESTful Webservices, Microservices, Web Data Scraping, SQL, AWS, Python.

#### **Certifications:**

- ✓ Certified Software Programmer in Python by Infosys Limited.
- Certified Talent Next Programmer in Java/J2EE by Wipro.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Application Development Associate**

OCT 2021 - JUN 2022

Accenture

 Hands on experience in Java, Spring Framework to design, build and configure applications to meet business process and application requirements.

Software Engineer JUN 2022 – NOV 2022

Envestnet Yodlee

Systems Engineer NOV 2022 – Present

Tata Consultancy Services

- Backend Java Developer in Data operations as part of core product development team to develop, integrate the new functionalities and feature enhancements in financial data aggregation products based on the website changes/updates.
- Created more than 20+ java-based data scraping and cleansing agents and reconciled data for more than 100+ financial institutes, increasing the data quality using web developed APIs in Java selenium, Jsoup and Spring Framework.
- In addition, using provider API calls to connect with FI endpoints using request-response data by user authentication and authorization.

## **PROJECTS**

# Data Aggregation Platform 🗹 | Java, Financial Data Scrapping, Spring Framework, SQL, JavaScript

- The core data aggregation product was built on top of java-based web scrapping and web API Ajax calls to fetch and store the financial account data from the financial institutes for aggregated end-users with ensuring data quality and providing data aggregation services to the customers based on the instant/batch/auto updates on the end-user aggregated accounts.
- Also facilitates Open Banking to customers with the help of provider interface and API calls to connect with FI by user authentication and authorization to get the financial account data.

## Business Insights Data Gatherer 🗹 | Java, Spring Boot, Web Scrapping, MongoDB, AWS, JavaScript

- The Data Gatherer API collects business overview data and business review details such as ratings, comments etc... from Google.
- The Report API will generate a business overview report with all available web content from most popular business platforms with ratings, followers count, and reviews including google reviews and business competitors in the market post data analysis on every parameter of business domain. For subscribed businesses, it will return more insightful data based on the customer ratings and reviews on the web with positive and negative impacts on the business based on the timeline and other parameters.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- > 5-Star badge in Problem Solving from Hacker Rank Platform | / prudhvirajmarga1
- Technical Expert award in Data Operations from the Client (Envestnet Yodlee)

#### HOBBIES

Playing Cricket, learning from the Internet, Watching Movies.